Hallelujah!
Let someone say:
"Send your power on me!"
Say, "Neighbour, welcome to the presence of Jesus".
Say, "Neighbour, Happy New Year in advance".
Say, "I am in His presence.
In His presence, there is fullness of love.
In His presence, fullness of power".
Let someone say, "Power - glory.
Glory - power!"
Give thanks to Jesus, give thanks to Him.
Thank You, Jesus!
Have your seat!
Say, "Neighbour, welcome to the presence of Jesus".
I don't know what you have been through this year.
But all I know is something new is about to happen.
Do you believe that?
It is something that can turn your life around.
Say, "Jesus loves me.
God loves me just as He loves any of His children".
Yes, Jesus loves me, Jesus loves you.
Never doubt the love of God in your life.
The Bible says that we have two loves - human love and God's love.
But human love is but a shadow of God's love.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Why?
Human love is conditional; God's love is unconditional.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Love cannot exist without relationship.
Why?
Because love can only be manifested where there is an object to be loved.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God wanted a love relationship so He created Adam.
When Adam sinned, that relationship was broken.
But the Bible says, God so loved the world that He planted His best seed, Jesus Christ,
to produce a family and today, millions are born again through this best seed.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This shows, this indicates that love is the golden thread that links God's creation.
Say, "Neighbour, love is the golden thread that links God's creation. Let love lead".
It brings us to our message this morning: AN EXTRAORDINARY RELATIONSHIP
Tell your neighbour, "AN EXTRAORDINARY RELATIONSHIP".
Let me take you to the Book of Matthew.
Jesus says, "You have heard that it was said, 'You shall love your neighbour and hate your enemy'.
But I say to you, love your enemies, bless those who curse you, do good to those who hate you,
and pray for those who spitefully use you and persecute you,
that you may be sons of your Father in Heaven;
for He makes His sun rise on the evil and on the good,
and sends rain on the just and on the unjust.
Therefore, you shall be perfect, just as your Father in Heaven is perfect."
Let someone say, "AN EXTRAORDINARY RELATIONSHIP".
We are here for an extraordinary relationship.
An extraordinary relationship does not begin with a love for people.
It begins with a love for God and that love overflows to people.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God's love is first love. Through His love, we love.
Let someone say, "There is no love without relationship".
Relationship means cooperation - where the people involved in that relationship
benefit or gain from each other.
We are one another's strength.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
A harmonious relationship - be it in your business, be it in your marriage -
a harmonious relationship is all about beneficial cooperation.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Beneficial cooperation means a symbiotic, a reciprocal relationship
based on the principle of mutual giving and receiving.
This is the relationship approved by God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
How can we achieve this today?
The man of God said that we must set aside our differences
to bring about cooperation and relationship among us.
We must set aside our differences to bring about what the other person lacks.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour, "I am because you are, you are because I am".
Say, "Neighbour, there is no such thing as a perfect relationship".
There is no perfect relationship because perfection eludes us all; we all hurt somewhere.
That is why today, many relationships are under repair because we lack love.
Today, as we are sitting, many relationships are under repair because we lack love.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There is no relationship without challenges.
God never promised that there would be no more trouble but He promised to see you through.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
For a relationship to come to stay, for a relationship to be stable,
it must go through thick and thin.
I mean, it must go through many experiences - both positive and negative.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Because personnel improvement and fulfillment comes from the continual process
of learning from both positive and negative experiences.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When challenges come, don't break.
Challenges force us to look inward and to discover
and to come up with the result that nobody knows you as you know yourself.
Look at every successful relationship you see today -
be it in their business, be it in their marriage -
you will see how much pain, how much trouble they underwent
before they came to a successful relationship.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Let someone say, "Challenges strengthen our relationship".
Say, "Neighbour, don't give up. Challenges strengthen our relationship".
That why we need to know this.
Don't break any relationship because of challenges.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, I am ready for an extraordinary relationship this morning.
I am ready for a new dawn in my relationship, in my marriage, in my life".
Say, "Neighbour, don't reject anyone because of today.
Don't reject him because of today.
Don't reject her because of today.
Don't reject them because of today".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Why?
Today, we lose friends because of differences.
Relationships break beyond repair because of life's challenges.
Don't allow weakness and confrontation to tear your relationship down or to pull you apart.
Rather, see that challenge as a means to come closer to God, to come closer together,
to be prepared for victory because victory is yours, in the name of Jesus!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Relationships break today because of differences and the uniqueness of the participants.
Relationships break because of unacknowledged and unrecognized differences
in the people involved in that relationship.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, our differences make us unique.
Your difference makes you unique".
It makes you unique; it is a feature that must be recognized on each person.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We must accept the differences in our personalities and the natural gift we are endowed with.
This is what we call beneficial cooperation.
Say, "I am because you are, you are because I am".
This feature must be recognized so that relationship can stand,
that relationship can be permanent, can endure.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, don't reject anyone because of today.
Where you are strong, I am weak; where I am weak, you are strong.
We are one another's strength".
If you reject anyone because of his weakness, you reject his strength.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you know the weakness of your friend, help him, instead of criticizing or rejecting him.
We must recognize this in order to have the victory.
Say, "Neighbour, a New Year is coming".
What is the way out?
There is no better way to celebrate the incoming year
than to reprogramme ourselves for an extraordinary relationship.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Are you ready for that?
An ordinary relationship can become an extraordinary relationship by looking up to Jesus.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, look up to Jesus".
No matter what you are passing through now - be it in your marriage, be it in your business -
look up to Jesus; He is the Restorer and the Repairer.
An ordinary relationship can become extraordinary by looking up to Jesus.
Remember, Jesus forgave those who mocked Him and even killed Him.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, are you ready to build that new relationship? Are you ready?"
The Bible says in the Book of Galatians 6:1 that there is a way out.
First and foremost, we must learn the guiding principle to maintain a successful relationship.
Say, "Neighbour, don't reject anyone on account of today because tomorrow is mystery".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Mystery means unknowable, secret, hidden.
Mystery means divine truth, divine revelation.
Say, "Neighbour, don't break relationships beyond repair because of today
because the person who is a thorn in your flesh today can be your saviour tomorrow.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, don't break any relationship beyond repair because of today
because the person who is a thorn to your flesh today can be your saviour tomorrow.
A broken person can be arranged for a seat of power
A broken person can be prepared for the throne, can be a leader tomorrow.
The person who is bad today can be the best tomorrow.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, an extraordinary relationship does not just happen, it is built".
Building that extraordinary relationship requires a new approach because a new year is coming.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
My brothers, as we said: There is no better way to celebrate this incoming year
than to programme yourself for an extraordinary relationship.
The Bible says in Galatians 6:1, there must be forgiveness because no relationship is perfect.
There must be forgiveness because no one is perfect on this earth.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Forgiveness offers us today the opportunity to reshape our relationship for the best which is yet to come.
Say, "Neighbour, forgiveness today offers me the opportunity
to reshape my relationship for the best which is yet to come.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Misunderstanding in relationship leads to greater understanding when Jesus is involved.
Let someone say, "Forgiveness strikes the root of all pain.
Forgiveness paves the way for a harmonious relationship even with your enemy".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Jesus said that when you love your enemy and pray for those who persecute you,
this releases you from the destructive emotions of anger, bitterness and revenge against others.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, the person most hurt by unforgiveness is you".
Say to yourself, "The person most hurt by unforgiveness is me".
When we fail to forgive, we find ourselves in a torture chamber.
We find ourselves wallowing in our own sins.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The harbouring of a spirit of unforgiveness breaks the communion with God.
Therefore, we should not come to a confrontation about sin with the intent of punishing the sin
or with the intent of harming the other person.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If we do not come to a settling account in this matter we find ourselves in grave danger.
Say, "Neighbour, are you ready for a new level in your relationship?
Are you ready to reshape your relationship in your business, home, marriage, life?
Are you ready?"
Say, "Don't give up.
Stay put; a new year is coming".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We should not enter the New Year with a heart full of offence, full of pain of the past.
If you enter the New year holding onto offence,
you are still living in the past and there is nothing new in the incoming year.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, we make the year new by the way we live it".
You make the year new by the way you live it.
You renew the covenant by the way you live it.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
How do we live it?
Say, "Neighbour, how do you make the year new?"
Say, "Give them another chance".
Give them another chance.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Now, I want you to look at your neighbour and to ask him this question.
Say, "Neighbour, do you find it difficult to forgive?"
Ask him.
If you find it difficult to forgive, then take a look back at your own life and answer this question.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Are you ready to ask the question?
Say, "Neighbour, are you ready? Let me ask you a question".
Say, "What has the Heavenly Father forgiven in your life?"
Think about it and tell your neighbour again.
What has the Heavenly Father forgiven in your life? Think about it.
Say, "Neighbour, how patient the Heavenly Father is with you - forgiving you day in, day out".
Say, "Neighbour, how merciful the Heavenly Father is with you".
When you ignore Him, when you disappoint Him, when you break His commandments,
His love upon you remains constant.
Do you find it difficult to forgive?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So brothers, this is the answer.
This is the key to make all things new.
Loving your enemy, forgiving those who sin against you will always seem unreasonable,
until you realise that we were enemies to God and He forgave us.
So loving your enemies, forgiving them will seem unrealistic
until we come to realise that we were enemies to God and He forgave us.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, if you are forgiven..."
Are you sure, you are forgiven?
I'm asking you, what is the state of your heart?
Say, "Neighbour, if you are forgiven, that forgiveness will produce in you a forgiving spirit towards others".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Therefore, let love lead.
Can we stand up in His presence.
Say, "Let love lead.
In your marriage - let love lead.
In your business - let love lead.
In your relationship - let love lead".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When you follow the light of love in this coming year,
nothing out of God's control can happen to you.
Say, "Neighbour, when you follow the light of love in this coming year,
no matter how thick the darkness, nothing out of God's control will happen to you.
Nothing out of God's control will happen to your marriage, to your life.
That is the promise of God.
God bless His Word, in Jesus' name.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT: Esther Mwelwa 21/3/19
RV: Mel Flowers 14/04/2019